#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/ sathiamayandi (LinkedIn)

## Top Skills

Business Development Leadership Digital Strategy

### Languages

Tamil (Native or Bilingual)
Chinese (Elementary)
English (Native or Bilingual)

#### Certifications

Machine Learning

Transformational Selling - Huthwaite SPIN

Neural Networks and Deep Learning
Executing Complex Programs
Emerging Partner

# Sathia Mayandi

CTO | Executive Leadership | Data Science, Machine Learning & AI | Product Strategy, Management, Design & Engineering | Data Analytics & Engineering | P&L Leadership & General Management Houston, Texas, United States

# Summary

I am a digital business and technology consulting leader with 15+ years of revenue growth, practice/capability development and general management experience in consulting services industry.

I have created and executed strategic plans for business unit/ practice growth with a 30% CAGR at a healthy contribution margin, driven revenue growth through

- farming (both ground up and strategic account development with over \$100 M in revenue),
- partnerships,
- ventures,
- and development of solution offerings.

My experience includes leading a team of 2000+ employees with a top percentile employee satisfaction record and working with clients in oil & gas, manufacturing, utilities and consumer goods industry with a top percentile client satisfaction record.

I am passionate about transforming business and operating models to create, capture or deliver value through digital strategy, effective use of digital technologies in the cloud, IoT, data, analytics, machine learning and artificial intelligence space.

A life long learning quest has led me to pursue executive programs from Harvard, Stanford, MIT, Kelley School of Business, Huthwaite, Franklin Covey, etc. In addition to having a master's degree in computer applications & a bachelor's degree in computer science, I am a Harvard Business School Alumnus with certification in general management.

My professional collaborations include advising small businesses/ startups and establishing the right connections and I promote social collaborations as a secretary for my under-grad, grad & HBS class.

# Experience

TeamStack.ai Chief Technology Officer 2022 - Present (1 year)

Executive Leadership, Product Management, Design & Engineering, Data Engineering, Data Science & Machine Learning, Technology Strategy,...

### PibyThree

Member of The Board of Advisors December 2022 - Present (5 months)

Harvard Business Review Member, HBR Advisory Council 2022 - Present (1 year)

A member of the Harvard Business Review Advisory Council, an opt-in research community of business professionals.

Tech Mahindra
Vice President - Data, Analytics & Al Business
2021 - 2021 (less than a year)

### Infogain

Associate Vice President- Digital, Analytics & Al Services - O&G,Utilities & Manufacturing Markets 2018 - 2021 (3 years)

Houston, Texas Area

As a Growth Leader, I was responsible for P&L and revenue growth in IoT, Data, Analytics, Artificial Intelligence & Cloud Consulting Services. My team leads business transformation and operational excellence of client businesses through Digital & Data Strategy Consulting, Digital Enablement of people, customers, operations, and effective use of IoT, Analytics, Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence & Cloud technologies

### Cognizant

Leader, Oil and Gas / Artificial Intelligence & Analytics Practices, Cognizant Technology Solutions 2002 - 2018 (16 years)

Houston, Texas Area

As a leader in the Oil & Gas Practice and Artificial Intelligence & Analytics Practices, I was responsible for Revenue & Profitability of my portfolio, Client Partnerships and was accountable for Customer Success. I have worked with several customers in North America and provided solutions in Digital Experience, Mobility, Content, Data Management and Analytics; Business Process Integration; IT Infrastructure Services; Application Development, Integration, Maintenance and Testing Services over a period of 15+ years.

# Education

Harvard Business School General Management Program

Harvard University
Harvard Business Analytics Program

MIT Sloan School of Management
Executive Education, Artificial Intelligence

Anna University

Master's degree, Computer Applications

Bharathidasan University
Bachelor's degree, Computer Science & Engineering